Swaraj Kumar Baboo

Software Engineer

Software Developer having 5+ years of experienced in all phase of software development lifecycle, from the concept to development and delivery. Proficient in various platforms and languages. Able to effectively self-manage during independent project, as well as handle a productive team.

swarajkumarbaboo@gmail.com



7008242243



Bengaluru, India

in linkedin.com/in/swaraj-kumar-baboo

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer

Ace Turtle Pvt. Ltd.

11/2022 - Present,

Bengaluru, Karnataka

Responsibilities

- O Create technical documents and flowcharts. Maintain and improve the performance of existing software.
- Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleagues and test and maintain software products to ensure strong functionality and optimization.
- o Expand existing software to meet the changing needs of our key demographics.

Software Engineer

Studio Graphene Pvt. Ltd.

06/2021 - 11/2022,

Gurugram, Haryana

Responsibilities

- O Develop software using RESTful APIs with Node.js, Express.js & AWS cloud services.
- o Capturing the best development practices in a way of common coding standards with the team that help to decrease code complexity and improve maintainability of the shared libraries and components.
- Develop intuitive software that meets and exceeds the needs of the company/client.
- O Write unit test cases & test functions before send it to QA's.

Software Developer

Agio Support Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

11/2019 - 06/2021,

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Responsibilities

- o Manage team of 12 developers handling end-to-end software developmentlife
- Make sure documents and other work products are prepared and stored correctly, and that revisions are managed.
- O Actively seek ways to improve software Development processes with team.

Full Stack Developer

Innovative Business Solutions

07/2017 - 09/2019.

Noida

- Responsibilities
- O Developed front-end & back-end website applications.
- Developed and modify back-end features of web applications using PHP & MVC Framework i.e. Codelgniter.
- Design Database architecture for web application.

EDUCATION

B. Tech

BPUT, Odisha

08/2013 - 06/2017,

Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India

12th(PCMIT)

Vedic Group of Institutions

07/2011 - 05/2013.

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Daphne

- O Daphne is a platform that helps asset managers and distributors to connect themselves and they can manage their funds, products and can see other potential distributors.
- It is based on Micro-service architecture and currently in MVP stage.
- Technology used: Node.js, Typescript, PostgreSQL, AWS services, Okta, React.js.

Frolo (https://www.frolo.com)

- O Frolo a combination of the words 'friends' and 'solo', it's an community/dating app for single parent.
- Technology used: Node.js, Typescript, MySQL, AWS services i.e. (cognito, elastic, lambda, dynamoDb, redis), PHP(Laravel), React

Cryptoknowmics.com (https://cryptoknowmics.com)

- Cryptoknowmics has emerged as one of a kind decentralized media portal, which closely monitors every aspect of the cryptocurrency
- Technology Used: Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Angular.js, PHP, AWS

TwoBrothrs.co.uk(https://twobrothrs.co.uk)

- O TwoBrothrs is an online food delivery app/web.
- Technology Used: Node.is, Socket.io, Google Geo Location Api, MongoDB, Next.js(React.js), React Native(App), AWS services.

LANGUAGES

Fnalish

Professional Working Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Riding Bikes

Playing Keyboard

R&D

Samalpur, Odisha, India